KUMAR AMAN

- x amnshrvstv@gmail.com
- +91-8109492904
- Pune, India
- ▶ Don't click me!
- in /k-aman/
- /amphoenix/

PROFILE

Seasoned Full Stack Web Developer having **4+ years** of experience in translating designs to code using React.js with TypeScript, JavaScript, Redux, HTML5, SASS, CSS3. Skilled in backend development using Node.js, Express.js, and database like MongoDB & PostgreSQL. Experienced in modern workflow tools, module bundling via Webpack and version control via Git/Perforce.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering, RGPV University June 2014 – June 2018 | India CGPA: **7.92/10**

SKILLS

Web Technologies:

JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Redux, Enzyme, Jest, Jekyll, HTML5, CSS3

Backend Technologies • • • • •

Node, Express, Graphql, Docker, Kubernetes, Kafka, Nginx, Redis

Database:

MYSQL, Firebase Storage, Dynamo DB, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$

Finance:

Derivatives, Fixed Income, Alternative Investments, Quantitative Methods

Others

AWS Services, S3, IAM, Cognito, Firebase

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Amdocs, Software Developer

March 2022 – present

- Devised and implemented a micro-frontend architecture for a product, which is now adopted globally by numerous companies, recognized for its superior adaptability and performance.
- Designed & developed scalable backend systems using Node & Express, leveraging Redis for caching, data retrieval speed by 40%.
- Implemented dynamic Redux store partitioning strategies to optimize performance and scalability in large-scale React applications.
- Led and mentored a team of junior professionals by actively contributing to the execution of task and resolving roadblocks faced by them.

AAIC (Startup), Software Engineer

June 2021 - March 2022

- Independently Conceptualized, Developed, and Deployed a SkillSage project from Scratch to Deployment.
- Utilized HTML5, CSS3, TypeScript, React, Redux and RESTful APIs to build Frontend.
- Increased Lighthouse score from 50% to 80% by optimizing JS bundles. Integrated Razorpay API for seamless payment processing and leveraged Git for version control.
- Project garnered positive feedback from users and stakeholders, leading to a 40% increase in website traffic and a 25% rise in sales revenue.

Freelancer UI Developer

2021 - 2022

- Handled enterprise security challenge: Cross-Site Scripting (XSS) Attack, Application Security.
- Incorporated **role-based authentication** using **AWS services**, and audio & video conferencing using **Agora**.

Cognizant, Programmer Analyst

December 2018 - April 2020

- Handled two projects concurrently while serving as SME.
- Automated image optimization using Grunt, minified JS and CSS, reduced page load times; received early promotion ahead of schedule.
- Spearheaded redesign of the client's flagship app, resulting in a **20% increase in user engagement**.

INTERNSHIPS

Summer Trainee, Tata Motors

June 2017 - July 2017

 Developed an internal tool to automate BIW & Trim Line QA and monitor floor worker facing applications, resulting in an improved click through rate of 7%.

Summer Intern, Bosch Paramobile

July 2016 - August 2016

• Developed product tours with **React** for a new feature, improving customer adoption by 25%.